The Small One is a animation, family film directed by Don Bluth.
Ordered by his father to sell an old mule called Small One, a Hebrew boy in
the ancient Holy Land takes the donkey to the Jerusalem market.
Finding no buyers there, the boy is about to give up when he meets a kind man named Joseph, who
buys Small One and uses the steed to take his pregnant wife Mary to Bethlehem.
Boy (voice), played by Sean Marshall.
Tanner (voice), played by William Woodson.
Father (voice), played by Olan Soule.
Guard (voice), played by Joe Higgins.
Joseph (voice), played by Gordon Jump.
Auctioneer (voice), played by Hal Smith.
The Small One (also known as A Christmas Miracle in the UK) is a 1978 American animated featurette produced by Walt Disney
Productions and released theatrically by Buena Vista Distribution on December 16, 1978, with a re-issue of Pinocchio (1940).
The story is based on a 1947 children's book of the same name by Charles Tazewell and was a project for the new
generation of Disney animators including Don Bluth, Jerry Rees, Henry Selick, Gary Goldman, and John Pomeroy.
The story tells of a young boy outside Nazareth, who must part
with his best friend, an old donkey named Small One.
He brings it to market, but no one is in need of a
"scrawny donkey", except for a tanner.
The film explores themes of holiday, virgin mary,
nativity, christmas, jesus christ.